In the last video,
在上一个视频中
you saw two of the main aspects of principal components.
你看到了主成分的两个主要方面
The first was the amount of variability captured by each component,
第一个是每个成分捕捉到的变化量
which we saw with the scree plot.
这是我们在碎石图中看到的
The second was the actual components themselves.
第二个是成分本身
In this notebook, you'll get a chance to explore these a little bit more yourself.
在这个 notebook 中 你将有机会更深入地了解这些
Let's read in the necessary libraries, as well as our data.
让我们先导入需要用到的库 以及我们的数据
Here are the top 30 images.
以下是前 30个图片
Now, let's perform PCA on our X matrix
现在 让我们使用之前视频中
using the do_pca function we've been using in the previous videos.
使用的 do_pca 函数在 X 矩阵上执行 PCA
Remember, this will return back the PCA model itself,
记住 这将返回 PCA 模型本身
as well as the matrix of the reduced features.
以及特征数量减少了的特征矩阵
In this case, we'll use 10 principal components.
在这种情况下 我们将使用 10个主成分
We'll want to pass it our X matrix,
We'll want to pass it our X matrix, 我们要把它传递给 X 矩阵
which is basically the images themselves.
它基本上就是图像本身
Now, let's try creating a scree plot using the model that we just created.
现在 让我们尝试使用我们刚刚创建的模型创建一个碎石图
Remember, each of these bars represents
记住 这个条形图中的每个柱
the amount of variability captured by each component.
都表示每个成分所捕获的变化量
So, the first component captures this amount,
所以 第一个成分捕获这个量
the second, this amount, and so forth.
第二个成分是这个量 等等
The line represents the total amount of
这条线表示在某个成分级别处
variability captured at a certain level of components.
累积捕获的总变化量
So, by the end of 10 components,
所以 到了 10个成分的末尾
we have about 30 percent of the original variability in
我们得到了这 10个成分所捕获的
the data that's being captured by those 10 components.
数据中约 30% 的原始变化量
Using this, we can fill in the dictionary below 10.42.
用这个 我们可以填写下面的字典
This one seems like the trickiest one. I'll come back to it.
10.42 ? 这个看起来是最棘手的一个 我们稍后再看它
The first component will always have the most amount of variability explained.
第一个成分总是可以解释最多的变化量
That's actually true.
这个是真的
It's always the case that the principal components will
在这种情况下 主成分总是希望
look to capture the most amount of variability remaining in the dataset.
捕获数据集中剩余可变性的大部分
Therefore, the first component will always capture the most,
因此 第一个成分将始终捕获最多
the second will capture the second most,
第二个成分将捕获第二多
and so on and so forth.
依此类推
You'll never see a later component that captures more variability than
你永远不会看到后面的成分
an earlier component of the total amount of
比前面的成分捕获更多的变化量
variability in the data explained by the first component.
即第一个成分所解释的数据中的变化量的总量
So, the first component looks like it explains 6.13 percent.
所以 第一成分看起来解释了 6.13%
So, that looks like answer c. Then the sum
所以 这看起来像答案 c
of the variability explained by all the components can be greater than 100 percent.
那么所有成分解释的变化量之和可以大于 100%
So, will never be the case that you will get a sum of the amount of
所有成分解释的变化量总和
variability explained by all the components greater than 100 percent.
永远不会大于 100%
The most amount of variability that the principal components can explain is
主成分能够解释的最大变化量
just the total amount of variability that the data had to begin with.
只是数据开始时的总变化量
So, therefore, only 100 percent.
因此 只有 100%
So, this statement here is false.
所以 这个陈述是错误的
Then, this 10.42 must be
然后 这个 10.42
the total amount of variability that's explained by the first two components.
应该是前两个成分解释的总变化量
So, if we see 6.13,
所以 如果我们看到 6.13
4.29, if we add those two together,
4.29 如果我们把这两个加起来
we get the 10.42.
我们得到 10.42
It looks like that turned out okay and we get a little bit of
看起来一切都很好
a reinforcer of the ideas that we just found.
我们刚刚发现的想法得到了一点加强
Now use the plot_component function from
现在使用 helper_functions 中的
the helper_functions to look at each of the components.
plot_component 函数查看每个成分
Use the results to assist with question five, down here.
利用结果来帮助回答下面的第五个问题
This takes two arguments,
这需要两个参数
if you remember from the video.
如果你记得视频内容
The first is the actual model,
第一个参数是实际模型
and then the second is the component that we want to plot.
然后第二个是要绘制的成分
By plotting the first component,
通过绘制第一个成分
you can see that it's pulling out, essentially is zero.
你可以看到它被取出 实际上是 0
So, this component looks like it will assist in identifying zero.
所以 这个成分看起来有助于识别 0
If we have 10 components and we're indexing them from zero to nine,
如果我们有10个成分  我们将它们从0 到 9 建立索引
this means that the zero is the component.
这意味着这个成分是 0
Then it says, which component looks like it's identifying a three?
然后它说 哪个特征看起来像是在识别一个3 ?
So, let's look at a couple of these other ones.
所以 让我们看看其他的几个
So, that one doesn't look like a three.
所以 那个看起来不像 3
That one doesn't really look like a three to me either.
在我看来 那也不算是 3
Oh! There we go. The fourth component.
哦！好了 第四个成分
So, remember these are indexed at zero,
所以 记住索引是从 0 开始的
but this looks a lot like a three.
但这看起来很像 3
Cool. Then from the notebook,
很酷  然后从这个 notebook 上
we've had an opportunity to look at these two major parts of PCA,
我们有机会看到 PCA 的这两个主要部分
the amount of variance explained by each component,
每个成分所解释的方差量
which is also called an eigenvalue,
也被称为特征值
and the principle components themselves,
以及主成分本身
which give us a weight for each of the pixels in the original images and how much they
这就给了我们原始图像中每个像素分配了一个权重
weigh into the individual principal components we
以及在我们的结果结束时
get back at the end of our results, right?
它们在各个主成分中的权重是多少 ?
These principal components are known as eigenvectors.
这些主成分被称为特征向量